KONSTANTIN CHERNYSHEV

NLP Data Scientist

@ kdchernyshev+job@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/kdchernyshev





EXPERIENCE

NLP Intern Jun 2023 **JetBrains Research, Netherlands Analysing Internal Representation of code generation models; To be updated. (Python) (PyTorch) (HuggingFace) (RL) (SkLearn) (DataLore)

- Jan 2021
 Present
- Managed a team of 9 people, planning, review, tech supervision;
- Conducted lectures on 'Packages and Modules', 'C-bindings';
- Boosted assignment-checking system (e.g 6x acceleration).

 (Management) (Python) (Teaching) (Docker) (PyTest) (Gitlab-CI) (Github-Actions)

NLP Data Scientist

& EPAM Systems, Serbia

☐ Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- Trained an unsupervised model for support ticket trends over time;
- Implemented a processing team predictive model, improving ticket processing efficiency by ~10s seconds per ticket for 100k t./year.
 (Python) (FastText) (SkLearn) (PyTorch) (PyTest) (Docker)

Apr 2020
- Jan 2022

- Managed 2-4 developers per project, liaising with clients;
- Introduced Align flow, CI/CD, code reviews, improved teamwork;
- Developed a highly-loaded 'roads quality' model on mobile data;
- Designed and developed a solution for scanned document analysis, trained a high mAP (~0.94) CV model for tables, pics, and stamps.
 (Python) (PyTorch) (HuggingFace) (SkLearn) (PyTest) (ONNX) (Docker) (Gitlab-Cl)

Research Intern

☐ Apr 2019 - Jan 2021

- **©LATNA Lab at Higher School of Economics**, Russia
- Conducted research on Compressed Sensing with I1 and I0 norms, resulting in a near SoTA recovery algorithm with faster convergence;
- Created Abstractive Summarization model using Knowledge Graphs.

 (Statistics) (Python) (HuggingFace) (CoreNLP) (SkLearn) (SciPy)

EDUCATION

Master of Arts (NLP) **Ouni. of Groningen & Saarland Uni., NL & DE **Description** **Commission** **Total Commission** **Total

Sep 2022 - Present

Erasmus Mundus "Language & Communication Technologies"; GPA: 8.2/10 (ongoing); + TA at Language Technology Project.

Post Graduate 2-year Program (Data Science)

Yandex School of Data Analysis, Russia

GPA: 8.9/10; + TA at Python Course.

Sep 2017 - Jul 2021

GPA: 9.1/10; + TA at Algorithms and Data Structures.

SUMMARY

Passionate NLP Scientist with 4+ years of experience, love NLG and arduous tasks;

HSE, Russia graduate BaSc with Honors, MsA Erasmus Mundus LCT till 2024. Has 5+ years of programming experience, 4+ years of Data Science Research experience: Startups, Yandex DS School, EPAM, and JetBrains; finished 8+ ML research projects.

SKILLS

- Data Science
 NLP DL ML NLU Summarization
 Graph Models (Speech) (CV) (RL)
- Frameworks
 HuggingFace PyTorch SkLearn
 Tensorflow) (NLPCore) (TorchText)
- Programming Languages
 Python (C++) (CUDA) (GoLang) (Dart)
- Development Tools
 git Docker Neptune.ai GitLab-Cl
 GitHub-Actions ONNX TensorRT
- Languages
 Russian English German Serbian

PUBLICATIONS

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Erasmus Mundus Scholarship 2022-2024;
- Placed 2nd at Moscow State hackathon "Digital Transformation 2021";
- Honours Bachelor's degree in CS;
- Largely improved Python course at YSDA, top-1 by students' rating.

PERSONAL

Cheerful and sociable person, keen on slackline and juggling, love music making creativity and strive to master the guitar.

(Music Production) (Juggling) (Slackline)